Guide to the John Hersey Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Hersey papers
1919-1992
YCAL MSS 707
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
65.23
(107 boxes)
The John Hersey papers contain writings, correspondence, printed and audiovisual materials, scrapbooks, and family and personal papers. The collection consists of ten small donations made by Hersey between 1944 and 1967 and an acquisition of a major part of his archive in 1992. The early gifts by Hersey contain drafts and proofs for multiple works dating from the early 1940s through mid 1960s, including the successful and popular A Bell for Adano (1944), Hiroshima (1946), and The Wall (1950). The later 1992 acquisition contains additional writings, as well as correspondence and clippings files relating to writings, correspondence, scrapbooks, audiovisual material, and personal papers. Correspondence includes large files for the publishers Alfred A. Knopf and Hamish Hamilton, the literary agent Otis and Williams, The New Yorker, and outgoing letters from Hersey to his mother. Writings include materials relating to Hersey's first book, Men on Bataan (1942), and numerous later works, including White Lotus (1965), The Walnut Door (1977), The Call (1985), and Blues (1987).
Hersey, John, 1914-1993
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from John Hersey by gift and purchase, 1944-1992.
October 2013 and August 2014 Acquisitions: Gift of Brook Hersey.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 68 contains restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 69-71 and 107 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Other material by or relating to John Hersey (various call numbers) can be found by searching the Uncataloged Acquisitions Database and Orbis (Yale's Online Catalog).
John Hersey (1914-1993)
John Hersey, American novelist and author, was born 17 June 1914 in Tientsin, China to missionaries Roscoe and Grace Baird Hersey. After the family returned to the United States in 1925, and settled in Briarcliff Manor, New York, Hersey attended public school, Hotchkiss School, Yale University (1936) and Clare College, Cambridge (1936-1937). Following his studies he worked for several years as a journalist, first for Time magazine (1937-1944) and then, after the Second World War, as a correspondent and editor for Life and The New Yorker. He later taught at Yale and served as Master of Pierson College (1965-1970). Hersey is the author of numerous works of fiction and non-fiction. He was awarded the Pulitzer Prize for his first novel, A Bell for Adano (1944) in 1945, and multiple awards, including the Anisfield-Wolf Award, for his second novel, The Wall (1950). Hersey died 24 March 1993 in Key West, Florida.
Biographical information taken from "John Hersey." Concise Dictionary of American Literary Biography. Detroit: Gale Research, 1998. Biography In Context. Web. 6 March 2013.
Scope and Contents
The John Hersey Papers contain writings, correspondence, printed and audiovisual materials, scrapbooks, and family and personal papers. The collection consists of ten small donations made by Hersey between 1944 and 1967 and an acquisition of a major part of his archive in 1992. The early gifts by Hersey contain drafts and proofs for multiple works dating from the early 1940s through mid 1960s, including the successful and popular A Bell for Adano (1944), Hiroshima (1946), and The Wall (1950). The 1992 acquisition contains additional writings, as well as correspondence and clippings files relating to writings, correspondence, scrapbooks, audiovisual material, and personal papers. Correspondence includes large files for the publishers Alfred A. Knopf and Hamish Hamilton, the literary agent Otis and Williams, The New Yorker, and outgoing letters from Hersey to his mother. Writings include materials relating to Hersey's first book, Men on Bataan (1942), and numerous later works, including White Lotus (1965), The Walnut Door (1977), The Call (1985), and Blues (1987).
Arrangement
Organized into thirteen groupings: April 1944 Acquisition, January 1947 Acquisition, December 1951 Acquisition, May 1952 Acquisition, December 1963 Acquisition, August 1964 Acquisition, December 1964 Acquisition, November 1966 Acquisition, December 1966 Acquisition, December 1967 Acquisition, March 1992 Acquisition, October 2013 Acqusition, Augut 2014 Acquisitions.
New Yorker (New York, N.Y.: 1925); American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Photographic prints; Sound recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Hersey, Grace Baird; Hersey, John, 1914-1993; Alfred A. Knopf, Inc; Hamish Hamilton Ltd; Otis and Williams
- April 1944 Acquisition, 0.21; (1 box)
  General note
  Former call number: Za Hersey.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of John Hersey.
  - A Bell for Adano, draft, typescript, corrected, [1944]; 2 (Box 1)
- January 1947 Acquisition, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Hiroshima, first draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 2)
- December 1951 Acquisition, 1947-1950; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Former call number: Za Hersey
  - The Wall, first draft, autograph manuscript, [1947-1949]; 6 (Box 3)
  - The Wall, first draft, autograph manuscript, [1947-1949]; 2 (Box 4)
  - The Wall, draft, typescript, corrected, [1950]; 5 (Box 5)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes letters from John Hersey dated November 27, 1951 and January 3, 1952
- May 1952 Acquisition, 0.21; (1 box)
  - "The Mechanics of a Novel," draft, typescript, [1952] (Box 6)
- December 1963 Acquisition, 1953-1956; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  - A Single Pebble, drafts and notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1953, undated; 7 (Box 7)
  - A Single Pebble, draft, typescript, and page proofs, 1956, undated; 2 (Box 8)
- August 1964 Acquisition, 1960; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  - The Child Buyer, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1960, undated; 8 (Box 9)
  - The Child Buyer, draft, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - The Child Buyer, page proofs and galley proofs, 1960; 4 (Box 11)
- December 1964 Acquisition, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  - The Child Buyer, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated; 2 (Box 12)
- November 1966 Acquisition, 1958-1959; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - The War Lover, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated; 4 (Box 13)
  - The War Lover, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1958, undated; 4 (Box 14)
  - The War Lover, galley proof and page proof, 1959, undated; 4 (Box 15)
- December 1966 Acquisition, 1959; 0.21; (1 box)
  - The War Lover, galley proof and specimen pages, 1959; 2 (Box 16)
- December 1967 Acquisition, 1965; 1; (1 box)
  - Too Far To Walk, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, page proofs and plate proof, 1965, undated; 9 (Box 17)
- March 1992 Acquisition, 1917-1990; 46.63; (54 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 68-70 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 71 (audio tapes): Use of original is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Writings, and Committee Reports and Other Material.
  The March 1992 Acquisition contains correspondence, writings by Hersey and others, scrapbooks, audiovisual material, and personal and family papers. Correspondence includes large files for the publishers Alfred A. Knopf and Hamish Hamilton, literary agent Otis and Williams, The New Yorker, and outgoing letters to Grace Baird Hersey. Other correspondence can be found in runs of alphabetized letter-general folders and within the Writings subseries. Writings in the acquisition include materials for Hersey's first book, Men on Bataan (1942), numerous later books, including White Lotus (1965), The Walnut Door (1977), The Call (1985), and Blues (1987), and shorter works.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 235.
  Purchased from John Hersey on various funds.
  - Correspondence
    - Letters from John Hersey to Grace Baird Hersey, 1929-1951; 24 (Box 18)
    - Engagement and wedding announcements, 1940 (Box 18)
    - Holiday cards, birth announcements, photos and ephemera, 1917-1940 (Box 18)
    - Postcards, 1929-1940 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence (A-Z), 1937-1951; 23 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (A-L), 1952-1963; 9 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (M-Z), 1952-1963; 8 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence (A-W), 1963-1966; 14 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence (Y-Z), 1963-1966 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence (A-Z), 1966-1969; 13 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence (Unsorted), 1966-1969; 3 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence (A-B), 1970-1973; 2 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence (C-Z), 1970-1973; 14 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence (A-G), 1974-1981; 6 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence (H-Z), 1974-1981; 11 (Box 23)
    - Letters and cables from Russia and family correspondence, 1942-1947; 7 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence with Knopf and Hamilton (London Publisher), 1943-1963; 22 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence with Knopf and Hamilton (continued), 1964-1981; 14 (Box 25)
    - Knopf royalty statements, 1969-1978; 3 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence with Hamilton, 1955-1978; 2 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence with Hamilton (continued), 1957-1976; 2 (Box 25)
    - New Yorker, correspondence and related material, 1946-1966; 3 (Box 26)
    - Clippings and ephemera, 1960-1968; 5 (Box 26)
    - Clippings and ephemera, 1961-1969; 2 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence with Otis and Williams (agent), 1946-1970; 17 (Box 27)
  - Writings
    - "The Death of Buchan Walsh," Atlantic Monthly, 1946 (Box 27)
    - "The Pen," Atlantic Monthly, 1946 (Box 27)
    - "Why Where You Sent Out Here?," Atlantic Monthly, 1946 (Box 27)
    - "States-Side Hat", 1946 (Box 27)
    - "Party of the Second Part", 1949, undated (Box 27)
    - "Then Out Into the World We Came", 1959, undated (Box 27)
    - "The Woman Who Took Gold Intravenously," Cosmopolitan, 1947 (Box 28)
    - "A Short Wait," New Yorker, 1947 (Box 28)
    - "Do You Like It Here?", 1947 (Box 28)
    - "The First Time I Died", 1947 (Box 28)
    - "In Touch," Atlantic Monthly, undated (Box 28)
    - "Hot Eyes", 1949, undated (Box 28)
    - "Sorry", 1949, undated (Box 28)
    - "Peggety's Parcel of Shortcomings", 1949, undated (Box 28)
    - "New China", 1941 February 14 (Box 28)
    - Early articles, book reviews; Life Magazine articles, 1937-1946; 25; (16 discs) (Box 28)
    - New Yorker articles, 1944-1945, undated; 6 (Box 28)
    - New Yorker articles (continued), 1944-1946, undated; 5 (Box 29)
    - "Chinese Medicine", 1946, undated (Box 29)
    - Life Magazine articles, 1945-1956; 2 (Box 29)
    - Reviews, 1947, undated; 2 (Box 29)
    - "Häftling No. 107907", 1947 (Box 29)
    - "Alternatives to Apathy", 1947, undated (Box 29)
    - Baruch pieces, research material, 1948; 4 (Box 29)
    - Marshall article for Collier's, 1947; 7 (Box 29)
    - "The Yearling Family", 1947-1950; 3 (Box 29)
    - "Yale's Greatest Class", 1951 (Box 29)
    - "Ingathering of Exiles", 1951; 2 (Box 29)
    - "AAK's Love Affair", 1952 (Box 29)
    - "School's Construction", 1953 (Box 30)
    - "The Girard Case", 1957 (Box 30)
    - "Winsted Flood ", 1955 (Box 30)
    - Truman articles, notes, correspondence and drafts, autograph manuscript, and galley proofs, 1950-1951; 18 (Box 30)
    - Girgus, Samuel Bruce, "Against the Grain: The Achievement of John Hersey", 1972; 2 (Box 30)
    - Letters to Hersey regarding his books, 1972; 18 (Box 31)
    - Berman, Murray A., "John Richard Hersey", 1956-1969 (Box 31)
    - Einhorn, Jodie, "The Life and Works of John Hersey", undated (Box 31)
    - Photographs. Suez Canal, undated; 2 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous short stories and writings, 1948-1965; 14 (Box 32)
    - "Hungary," New Yorker, 1957; 2 (Box 32)
    - "Mississippi," Saturday Evening Post, 1964; 2 (Box 32)
    - "A Test of Heart and Mind: America's Cup Trials," Life Magazine, 1964 September 4 (Box 32)
    - "Our Romance With Poverty," American Scholar, 1964 (Box 32)
    - "To Whom a Vote Is Worth a Life", undated (Box 32)
    - The President, drafts, autograph manuscript, master galleys, reproductions, and notes, 1974-1976; 18 (Box 33)
    - Men on Bataan, notes and background material, scrapbook, correspondence, and galley proofs, 1942; 13 (Box 34)
    - Into the Valley, CBS television workshop script, correspondence, clippings, and ephemera, 1942-1970; 8 (Box 34)
    - A Bell for Adano, first draft, typescript and typescript carbon, outline, notes, correspondence and reviews, 1942-1968; 19 (Box 35)
    - The Wall, notes, drafts, typescript carbon, galley proofs, and correspondence, 1947-1955; 2 (Box 35)
    - The Wall (continued), 1947-1955; 11 (Box 36)
    - A Single Pebble, correspondence, reviews, clippings, 1956-1965; 2 (Box 36)
    - Hiroshima, typescript carbon; reviews and news stories; correspondence with New Yorker, etc.; diary of Kiyoshi Tanimoto, with account of JH research, pp. 172f; survey of radio comments on the New Yorker issue; New Yorker galleys; reading on audiotape, Vassar, 11/14/65, 1945-1965; 5; (1 audiotape) (Box 36)
      Includes 1 7" reel-to-reel audiotape
    - Hiroshima, clippings and articles, 1946; 17 (Box 37)
    - Hiroshima (continued), 1946; 7 (Box 38)
    - The War Lover, correspondence, reviews, jacket designs and sample pages, 1958-1961; 3 (Box 38)
    - The Marmot Drive, correspondence, reviews, printer's typescript, galley proofs, 1953; 6 (Box 38)
    - The Child Buyer, correspondence, reviews; sample pages, reviews of the play, correspondence and related material, 1960; 6 (Box 39)
    - The Wall, reviews, clippings and related printed material, 1950; 10 (Box 39)
    - White Lotus, correspondence, reviews, notes, printer's typescript, carbon of transcript, galley proofs and advance proofs, 1965-1973; 3 (Box 39)
    - White Lotus (continued), 1965-1973; 5 (Box 40)
    - Under the Eye of the Storm, working carbon, sample pages, 1967; 7 (Box 40)
    - Under the Eye of the Storm (continued), 1967 (Box 41)
    - White Lotus, typescripts, 1967; 13 (Box 41)
    - The Wall, notes, revisions and typescript, 1945-1950; 4 (Box 41)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident, addresses, notes, transcriptions of interviews and printer's typescript, 1965-1968; 7 (Box 42)
    - Men on Bataan, autograph manuscript, working copy and notes, 1942; 6 (Box 42)
    - A Bell for Adano, first draft, outline for book, forward and notes, 1945 (Box 42)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident, research material and carbon copy, 1967-1968; 3 (Box 42)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident (continued), 1967-1968; 5 (Box 43)
    - The Wall, typescript, 1950; 10 (Box 43)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident, 1967; 2 (Box 43)
    - "Treadup," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 43)
    - Unsorted writings, undated; 7 (Box 44)
    - My Petition For More Space, book covers, undated (Box 44)
    - Saturday Review. Controversy regarding Hersey article, 1976 (Box 44)
    - Too Far to Walk, correspondence, reviews, notes, galleys, sample pages and jacket covers, 1965; 4 (Box 44)
    - White Lotus, Annals of My Skin, first draft of what became White Lotus; second draft; notes; revisions; rejected chapters, 1965; 3 (Box 44)
    - White Lotus (continued), undated; 8 (Box 45)
    - My Petition for More Space, printer's typescript, 1974 (Box 45)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident, notes, court transcripts, audiotapes, photographs, research, news clippings and correspondence, 1967; 7 (Box 45)
      Includes 27 2.5" reel-to-reel audiotapes
    - The Algiers Motel Incident (continued), 1967; 14 (Box 46)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident (continued), 1967; 4 (Box 47)
    - Unidentified file cards, undated; 2 (Box 47)
    - Letter to the Alumni, notes and background materials, correspondence, reviews, printer's typescript and galleys proofs, 1970; 10 (Box 48)
    - Here to Stay, printer's typescript and galley proofs, 1962; 3 (Box 48)
    - "The Writer's Craft," notes and drafts, 1967 (Box 48)
    - "The Fable of Jefferson's Island," drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1946; 2 (Box 48)
    - The Marmot Drive, autograph manuscript, first draft typescript carbon, second draft, working copy, cuts, 1946; 4 (Box 49)
    - "Of Men and War," notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 49)
    - The Writer's Craft, setting copy, 1974; 5 (Box 49)
    - "Out," typescript and autograph manuscript of United Nations film, 1957 (Box 49)
    - The Wall, notes, 1945-1950; 3 (Box 49)
    - Book on Education. Drafts of 4 chapters and notes on cards, 1954-1956; 8 (Box 50)
    - Here to Stay, drafts, correspondence and reviews, 1962; 3 (Box 50)
    - "The Sail Baker Dog," book written in 1943, some material later used in The War Lover. Draft, typescript, and correspondence (Box 50)
    - The Child Buyer, play script, first draft with notes, final script and correspondence. Film script by Lee Minoff. Out. A film made for the United Nations on Hungarian refugees in Austria after Hungarian uprising (1956): JH script, 1957, 1956-1959 (Box 50)
    - The Child Buyer (continued), 1956-1959; 4 (Box 51)
    - Education research and notes, 1954-1956; 4 (Box 51)
    - Here to Stay, correspondence and clippings, 1963 (Box 51)
    - The Conspiracy, correspondence, reviews, notes, outlines, revisions, printer's typescript and galley proofs, 1972-1975; 3 (Box 51)
    - The Conspiracy (continued), 1972-1975; 9 (Box 52)
    - The Writer's Craft, correspondence and reviews, 1975 (Box 52)
    - Ralph Ellison, notes, permissions and correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 52)
    - Writings On Israel. Successors, New Yorker, draft (photocopy), proofs and printed versions. I Can See Time, Saturday Review, notes, 1974; 2 (Box 52)
    - "Sailing with Kingman Brewster", 1977 (Box 52)
    - "Lillian Hellman," New Republic, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous writings and correspondence, 1960-1980 (Box 52)
    - Printed material, 1959-1974 (Box 52)
    - "The Sail Baker Dog," drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 52)
    - "Book on Russian Music," notes and draft, typescript carbon, 1944; 2 (Box 52)
    - "Book on Russian Music" (continued), 1944 (Box 53)
    - "Kilroy," draft, autograph manuscript and typscript, undated (Box 53)
    - My Petition for More Space, typescript and typescript (photocopy), printout, reviews and correspondence, 1973; 6 (Box 53)
    - Ralph Ellison, photocopy, undated; 1; (4 audiotapes) (Box 53)
      Includes 4 2.5" reel-to-reel audiotapes
    - M.I.T., 1975-1976 (Box 53)
    - "Successors," New Yorker, 1974 (Box 53)
    - The Algiers Motel Incident, correspondence and notes, 1968-1969 (Box 53)
    - Pierson College correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 53)
    - New Haven Defense Trust, 1970-1972 (Box 53)
    - Jerusalem Committee, 1973 (Box 54)
    - US-China Writers correspondence, 1982 (Box 54)
    - My Petition for More Space, computer printout, photocopy of proof, notes, reviews and correspondence, 1973; 3 (Box 54)
    - Hersey interview about John Kennedy, 1976 (Box 54)
    - Material related to Hersey's article on the justice system, 1970-1972; 2 (Box 54)
    - Yale College. Hersey's seminar and related correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 54)
    - Seven Springs Farm. Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 54)
    - College Board Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 54)
    - Yale Repertory Theater, 1972 (Box 54)
    - Israel, notes and correspondence, 1975 (Box 54)
    - "Triumph of Numbers," article with notes and correspondence for the Atlantic Monthly, 1980 (Box 54)
    - The Walnut Door, draft, typescript, outlines, revisions, page proofs, dead matter, reviews and correspondence, 1977-1981; 3 (Box 54)
    - The Walnut Door (continued), 1977-1981; 7 (Box 55)
    - The Wall, theater production contract, notes, correspondence and other writings, 1960-1964; 5 (Box 55)
    - "The Year of the Triphammer," draft, autograph manuscript, proofs and correspondence, 1978 (Box 55)
  - Committee Reports and Other Material
    - Westport Connecticut Democratic Town Committee, Rules, 1949
    - Writers' Board for World Government; Myth, that Threatens the World, 1949
    - Lauterbach Award, 1952 (Box 55)
    - Fairfield Citizens' School Study Council, salary study, 1952 (Box 55)
    - National Citizens' Commission for the Public Schools, White House Conference on Education, 1955 (Box 55)
    - Westport Citizens' School Study Council, 1949-1952 (Box 55)
    - Connecticut Committee for Gifted Children, 1951-1957; 2 (Box 55)
    - Connecticut Committee for Gifted Children (continued), 1951-1957; 4 (Box 56)
    - Fairfield Citizens' School Study Council. Report on reading, later published in Life, notes and correspondence, 1953-1954; 9 (Box 56)
    - National Citizens' Council for Better Schools. Evaluation, 1954 (Box 56)
    - Visiting Committee, Harvard Graduate School of Education, 1961-1966 (Box 56)
    - "The Legend of the License," Yale Review, 1980; 2 (Box 56)
    - The President, reviews and correspondence, 1975; 2 (Box 56)
    - Aspects of the Presidency, reviews, draft of preface, correspondence and proofs, 1980-1981; 2 (Box 56)
    - "Truman In Office," New Yorker article, related correspondence and notes, 1951-1973; 3 (Box 57)
    - Knopf contracts and royalty statements (copies), 1966-1978; 2 (Box 57)
    - Report of the National Commission on New Technology Uses of Copyrighted Works, 1976-1978 (Box 57)
    - Laura Baggiani, "John Hersey tra giornalismo e narrativa", 1977-1978 (Box 57)
    - Commission on Literature. National Council of Teachers of English, 1964-1966 (Box 57)
    - Weston School Board Policy Study, 1964-1965 (Box 57)
    - National Committee for the Support of Public Schools, 1963-1966; 2 (Box 57)
    - Ginzburg, Natalia. I Married You Just For The Fun Of It, translation by Hersey, with notes and draft, typescript, 1974; 2 (Box 57)
    - "Pictorial Art," scrapbook style account of the history of art written by Hersey, 1936; 5 (Box 58)
    - Adlai Stevenson speeches, notes and related material, 1956 (Box 58)
    - Authors League of America, 1976; 2 (Box 58)
    - The Writer's Craft, galley proof, introduction by Hersey, 1974 (Box 58)
    - Photocopying issues, 1976 (Box 58)
    - Computer software. Notes, committee reports and related correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 58)
    - My Petition for More Space, word count, notes, original cover layout and related material, 1974; 2 (Box 58)
    - Ralph Ellison, notes and correspondence, 1973; 2 (Box 58)
    - Copyright and software reports with related material, 1973-1977 (Box 58)
    - Copyright and software reports with related material (continued), 1973-1977; 4 (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous notes, clippings and writings, 1970-1979 (Box 59)
    - Israel. Article with notes, clippings and correspondence, 1974 (Box 59)
    - "The Myth that Threatens the World", 1949 (Box 59)
    - Truman State of the Union Speech, 1952 (Box 59)
    - "Reappraisal of Far Eastern Policy", 1965 (Box 59)
    - Governor's Committee on Libraries, 1962-1963 (Box 59)
    - Yale University Council, 1966 (Box 59)
    - Committee on Yale College, 1964-1965 (Box 59)
    - Yale College Committee Report. Dropouts, 1965; 5 (Box 59)
    - Council for Better Schools. Evaluation, 1958; 7 (Box 59)
    - Intelligence, Choice and Consent. Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1959; 3 (Box 60)
    - Speaking invitations, 1965-1966; 6 (Box 60)
    - New Haven Half-Way House, 1966 (Box 60)
    - Yale University Committee on Admissions, 1962-1964; 3 (Box 60)
    - Volunteers for Stevenson, 1956 (Box 60)
    - Under the Eye of the Storm, draft, autograph manuscript, and master galley proofs, undated; 7 (Box 60)
    - Aspects of the Presidency, 1980; 2 (Box 60)
    - The Call, draft, typescript, 1985; 2 (Box 60)